billtrust.com 2019-02-03

# Privacy Policy | Billtrust

This Privacy Policy explains Billtrust’s™ practices regarding the collection of personal information that is gathered through its website, [www.billtrust.com](https://www.billtrust.com/)(the “Site”) through the delivery of its solutions (the “Solutions) and through interactions via phone, email and other communication channels. 

**By visiting the Site or using the Solutions, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. We suggest that you review this Privacy Policy periodically, as it may be updated from time to time. This Privacy Policy was last revised in April 2018.**

**What We Collect**

_Collection of Information You Give Us._   Billtrust collects personal information about our users only during the secure order process, during the registration for our Solutions and during the use of our Solutions. We collect certain personal information, including your name, email address, phone number, shipping address, credit card company, credit card number and expiration date, credit card billing address, and invoicing information.

_Automatic Collection of Information.  _ For membership access areas, we require that you accept a cookie, which is a small file that is transferred to your computer through your web browser. These cookies help keep track of your login information to speed up the login process, and in certain cases we store your preferences to help tailor our site content to your interests. This is only for functionality reasons, and your personal information is never shared with anyone else. These cookies are also only collected by our sites; there are no third party cookies that are placed on your computer. The “help” portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive new cookies or how to disable cookies altogether. If you reject cookies, you may not be able to participate in certain functionality and membership features, as described above.

_Do Not Track.  _ Do Not Track (DNT) is a privacy preference that users can set in some web browsers, allowing users to opt out of tracking by websites and online services. At the present time, the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) has not yet established universal standards for recognizable DNT signals, and therefore, Billtrust and the Site do not recognize DNT.

**What We Share**

Billtrust respects your right to privacy. All of the information we collect is kept strictly confidential. It is not shared or sold to third parties, except as necessary to deliver the Site and Solutions to you. We have a strict policy of not selling our customers’ email addresses, any personally identifying information (PII) and are completely anti-spam.

The data we collect may be used in the aggregate to give us demographic information about the entire Billtrust audience, and in order to help us create, develop, operate, deliver, and improve our products, services, content and advertising, and for loss prevention and anti-fraud purposes. We may also include contact information and payment preference information for our user’s customers in our “Business Directory,” provided that such contact information shall be kept confidential and not disclosed to any third party other than Billtrust’s own trusted subcontractors.  We may also use personal information for internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis, and research to improve Billtrust’s products, services, and customer communications.  The information you provide (name, address, etc.) allows us to keep you informed about upgrades, products and services of Billtrust, its affiliates and other third parties that we believe may be of interest to you. If you are a registered user of one of our products, we will only send information regarding your product or any assistance which you may require.

In the event that all or a part of Billtrust is bought, sold, or otherwise transferred, or is in the process of a potential transaction, personal information that you have provided for use will likely be shared for evaluation purposes and included among the transferred business assets.

We may also disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on Billtrust or our Site.

**Review and Update Your Information**

If you would like to modify, update or delete information that is collected through the ordering or registration process, please contact [support@billtrust.com](mailto:support@billtrust.com).

**Children’s Privacy**

Billtrust, including the Site and Solutions, are not directed at children, and Billtrust does not knowingly solicit or collect personally identifiable information online from children under the age of 13. If Billtrust learns that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personally identifiable information online without prior verifiable parental consent, it will take all reasonable measures to delete such information from its databases and to not use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required or allowed by law). If you become aware of any personally identifiable information we have collected from children under 13, please contact us at [support@billtrust.com](mailto:support@billtrust.com).

**How We Notify You of Changes**

This Privacy Policy may be updated and revised from time to time, and we will post the current version of this Privacy Policy at [www.billtrust.com](https://www.billtrust.com/). You agree that the personal information we gather now will be subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of use.  We may contact you through email regarding material, retroactive changes to our Privacy Policy or practices, but you should check the Site periodically to review any changes. In order to receive communications from Billtrust regarding, among other things, our privacy practices, it is important that the email address you have on record with Billtrust is kept up to date.

**How We Protect Your Information**

We have numerous security measures in place to protect your personally identifiable information. Our employees are made aware of these measures when they start working at Billtrust. Any time there is a change in security measures, all employees are notified of the change. We are using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption for your credit card transactions and for all transmission of your billing information.

We do share your credit card information with a third party only for verification purposes. All customer information available to internal employees is only accessible on our internal company network.

Billtrust uses strict precautions to keep the personal information disclosed to us secure. However, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties which receive the information.

**EU-US Privacy Shield**

To the extent the Site or Solutions involves the collection of personal data of our clients or their customers in the European Economic Area, Billtrust may transfer that personal data to the United States for processing and storage. Billtrust handles any such personal data in adherence with the EU-US Privacy Shield and has certified compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfers, Security, Data Integrity & Purpose Limitation, Access, Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. To access the Privacy Shield List and to find details of our certification, please see [https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). Also, for more specific information please review our Privacy Shield Policy.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

This privacy policy describes how we may share your information, if at all, with other parts of our business and with our service providers for direct marketing purposes, explained above under “What We Share.”  You may contact us with any questions, or to request a list of third parties to whom we may disclose information for marketing purposes and the categories of information we may disclose.

**Billtrust’s Data Protection Officer (DPO)**

VeraSafe has been appointed as Billtrust’s DPO in accordance with Article 38 of the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR). VeraSafe can be contacted in addition to Billtrust only on matters related to the processing of personal data and to exercise your rights under the GDPR. To make such an inquiry, please contact VeraSafe at:

**Billtrust’s Data Protection Officer (DPO)**

VeraSafe  
22 Essex Way #8203 Essex, VT 05451 USA  
+1 (888) 376-1079  
Email: jim@verasafe.com

**Billtrust’s GDPR Article 27 EU Representative**

VeraSafe has been appointed as Billtrust’s representative in the European Union for data protection matters, pursuant to Article 27 of the General Data Protection Regulation of the European Union. VeraSafe can be contacted in addition to Billtrust only on matters related to the processing of personal data. To make such an inquiry, please contact VeraSafe using this contact form: https://www.verasafe.com/privacy-services/contact-article-27-representative. Alternatively, VeraSafe can be contacted at:  

**VeraSafe Czech Republic s.r.o**

Klimentská 46  
Prague 1, 11002  
Czech Republic

| **VeraSafe Ireland Ltd**

Unit 3D North Point House  
North Point Business Park  
New Mallow Road  
Cork T23AT2P  
Ireland  
  
---|---  
  
**Billtrust’s GDPR Article 27 EU Representative**

VeraSafe has been appointed as Billtrust’s representative in the European Union for data protection matters, pursuant to Article 27 of the General Data Protection Regulation of the European Union. VeraSafe can be contacted in addition to Billtrust only on matters related to the processing of personal data. To make such an inquiry, please contact VeraSafe using this contact form: https://www.verasafe.com/privacy-services/contact-article-27-representative. Alternatively, VeraSafe can be contacted at:  

**Contact Us**

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us at [support@billtrust.com](mailto:support@billtrust.com).
